To celebrate the Gintama anime becoming a movie
& breaking roughly one million in DVD sales,
(新八)ｱﾆﾒ『銀魂』 映画化決定＆
ＤＶＤ だいたい➡
百万本突破記念で始まった
第二回 ｷｬﾗｸﾀｰ人気投票｡
we held the second character
popularity poll.
However, someone unsatisfied
with the results
しかし その投票結果を
よしとしない何者かが➡
attacked Yamazaki-san in 9th
place to slide the ranking.
９位の山崎さんを襲撃し
人気順位に変動を起こした｡
This caused the girls, led by my sister,
to go for the kill before being killed.
これを受けて
姉上をはじめとする女性陣が➡
攻められる前に攻めよ と
動き始め➡
Hideaki Sorachi, the original author at 15th
place, was the first to be taken out.
まずは 15位 原作者 空知英秋が
始末されてしまった｡
[Please wait one moment.]
Then the anime staff attempted
to cancel this week's episode
さらに これを受けた ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌは
原作者不在を理由に➡
using the author's absence
as an excuse.
今週からの放送休止を画策するが
そんなｼｰﾝは先週のどこにもない｡
But such scene does not exist
in last week's episode...
With the original author gone,
what will happen to this show?
果たして 原作者不在のまま
このｱﾆﾒはどうなってしまうのか？
And how are we suppose to pull off
another 30 minute show this week?!
今週も 30分 いったい どうやって
埋めればいいんだろうか？
《あっ！
なんとか 画面が元に戻ったぞ｡
The screen's back to normal somehow.
That gorilla author must have
recovered after a week.
あのｺﾞﾘﾗ原作者 １週間で
なんとか 峠は越えたらしい｡
That's a relief.
よかった… 原作者死亡で
番組終了という➡
At the very least, this show won't be
canceled because the author died.
最悪の事態だけは
避けられたみたいだ｡
In any case, I must get
to Gin-san quickly...
よし！ とにかく 今は
銀さんのもとへ急がなきゃ｡
I can't let this popularity poll...
これ以上
この番組の人気投票を… いや》
No...
I cannot allow those wretched fiends to have their
way with this distorted, yet beautiful world!
《この醜くも美しい世界を
ﾔﾂら 外道の好きにはさせん！》
♪♪～
[Gintama]
[Episode 182]
[Farewell, Friend...]
[Artwork by: Cyborg Sorachi]
[Original story by: Gudonson]
[Note: A spoof on Buronson, the writer
of the manga "Fist of the North Star."]
Here I come!
いくぞ！ 闇将軍 家康!!
Dark Shogun Ieyasu!!
What the?!
《って… 作風 まるっきし
変わってっけど これ!!
The art style just changed
dramatically here!!
Who the hell is Cyborg Sorachi?!
さっきの ｻｲﾎﾞｰｸﾞ空知って誰!?
愚純尊って誰!?
Who the hell is Gudonson?!
Who the hell is Dark Shogun Ieyasu?!!
闇将軍 家康って 誰だ!?》
[Gotta love a glass of oil after finishing a draft!!
Mr. Cyborg Sorachi is whirring away!]
This program is brought to
you by OEDO Records,
Viper Industries, and the
following sponsors.
What's with the damn sponsor
message rolling like that?!
《って… 何 普通に
提供に流れ込んでんだ！
A glass of oil after finishing a draft?!
｢原稿あけの一杯のｵｲﾙが
最高!!｣って➡
Sorachi's been turned into a cyborg!
これ 完全に ｻｲﾎﾞｰｸﾞ化
されてんじゃん 空知！
Sorachi, you managed to survive,
一命はとりとめたけど
作風 まったく別人に➡
but your style turned into someone
completely different!
なっちゃってんじゃん
空知！
And the drawings are too detailed!
つうか これ
絵 描きこみすぎだろ！
We won't last to the end of our
fourth season at this rate!
こんな作風じゃ
４年目いっぱい もたねえぞ！
I appreciate Mr. Gudonson for
helping out with the story,
愚純尊先生も
原作協力 ありがたいけど➡
but he obviously has no clue
to what this show's about!
まったく 世界観 わかってねえ！
少しは読んでこいよ!!
Could you at least read
some of the manga?!
ん!?》
Huh?!
The land of the samurai!!
＜侍の国… ｵﾚたちの国が➡
There was a time, long ago, when our
country was called by that name!!
そう言われていたのは
今は昔の話!!＞
《って… やらすな!!
Cut it out!
That's not what I meant when
I said read the damn manga!
少しは読んでこいって
そういう意味じゃねえ!!
It's not about matching up the opening
narration and the teaser!
ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝとｱﾊﾞﾝ 合わせりゃ
いいってもんじゃねえだろ!!
What?! Another change?!
なに!? また 絵が…｡
Are the artist and original author
fighting over the theme?!
もしかして 作画と原作
漫画論で ｹﾝｶ おっ始めた!?
Hey, stop that!
おい やめろ！ お前ら 今は
仲よくしろ!! 何 考えてんだ!?
Get along now!
What are you thinking?!
What is the editor doing?!
編集 何やってんだよ!!
The artist and author would always
get into a fight if they meet!
作画と原作は
会ったら ｹﾝｶすっから➡
That's why the editor is suppose to act as
the mediator so things can go smoothly!
編集が間に立って
うまいこと 会わせないで➡
It's common sense, damn it!
打ち合わせすんのが 常識だろ！
『ﾊﾞｸﾏﾝ｡』みたいにいかねえんだよ!!
[Note: Bakuman is a manga about two kids aiming to
become manga artists. By the creators of Death Note.]
It doesn't work like Bakuman!
And the anime staff should
be able to do something!
つうか ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌ
なんとかできるだろ！ ｻﾎﾞって…｡
Stop slacking!
あっ！ 終わった!!
Ah.
It's over!
また 終わったぞ！
どうすんだよ!? これ！
It's over again!
What are we supposed to do?!
We still have over 20 minutes left!
今週 まだあと 20分以上
残ってんぞ！ どうすんだ！》
What are we supposed to do?!
[I'll work extra hard to make up for the missing Mr. Gudonson. Please show your support for the woeful warrior, Cyborg Sorachi!]
This program is brought to you
by Club Fugly, Senbokyo Inn,
and the following sponsors.
I-It's back to normal!
《も… 元に戻った！
よかった…｡
That's good.
Looks like Cyborg and Gudonson were
able to settle their differences.
ｻｲﾎﾞｰｸﾞも 愚純尊も
和解できたみたいだ｡
Don't get into another fight.
もう ｹﾝｶすんなよ！
仲よく やっていこう｡
Let's all get along.
All right, back to business...
よし！ 仕切り直して…｡
Huh? Mr. Gudonson!!
ん？ 愚純尊先生!!
He got taken out!!
消された！ 愚純尊先生
ｻｲﾎﾞｰｸﾞに抹殺された!!》
Mr. Gudonson got eradicated
by the Cyborg!!
["Popularity Polls Can Burn in Hell"]
Gin-san!
銀さ～ん！ 大変です！
大変なんです 銀さん！
It's terrible!
It's terrible, Gin-san!
愚純尊先生が！ 銀さん！
Mr. Gudonson has been...
Gin-san!
《遅かった！
I was too late...
He's already been attacked...
すでに 何者かに襲撃を受けた後！
No...
いや… でも 順位が
繰り上がってないということは➡
If my ranking hasn't gone up, Gin-san
and everybody else are still safe.
銀さんたちも無事なはず｡
But who did this...?
でも いったい
誰が こんな…》
(ざわめき)
I see...
《そうか… 誰が犯人とか
誰が 誰を狙ってるとか➡
It no longer matters who the perpetrators
are or who they're after...
そんなこと もう関係ないんだ｡
ﾎﾞｸより下の人たちはもう…
みんな 敵！》
Everyone below me is an enemy!
Come on down, Shinpachi.
(お登勢)ちょいと下りておいでよ
新八｡ 私たちのところまで｡
To where we are.
I-I'll pass...
え… 遠慮しときま～す｡
Hey, he's running for it!
あ！ 逃げたぞ！ 捕まえろ！
Catch him!
If we drag him down,
we'll all go up a spot!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｱｲﾂを引きずりおろせば
一つ順位が上がるよ ﾃﾒｴら！
追え！ 追うんだ～っ！
After him! After him!
ｷﾞｬｰｯ！
I didn't realize the situation was so dire!
《まさか ここまで
事態が進行していたなんて！
街中 敵だらけじゃないか～！》
This town is filled with enemies!
わぁ～っ！
ぐはっ！
うぅ…｡
あそこだ！ 追え！
Over there!
After him!
It's no use!
《ﾀﾞﾒだ！ 逃げ切れない！》
I can't get away!
H-He disappeared...
き… 消えた!?
どこへ行きやがったんだ！
Wh-Where did he go?
捜せ！ 草の根分けても
捜しだすんだよ ﾃﾒｴら！
Find him!
Search behind every blade of grass!
They're gone?
(銀時)行ったか…｡
(沖田)えぇ｡
Yeah, it's safe now.
もう 大丈夫みたいでぇ｡
銀さん！ 沖田さん！
Gin-san! Okita-san!
でっけぇ声 出すんじゃねぇよ！
旦那 ｱﾝﾀのほうが 声でかいです｡
Don't talk so loudly!
Boss, you're louder.
ど… どうして…
なんで この２人が…｡
H-How...
Why are the two of you together?
いったい
どういう組み合わせですか？
What kind of combination is this?
見ただろう ﾃﾒｴも｡
街中 あの調子だ｡
Didn't you see them?
The whole town is like that.
こんな状態じゃ 信用できるﾔﾂも
限られてくんだろうが｡
There are only a few people
you can trust in this situation.
いつもは信用できねぇけど
ｵﾚに次ぐ ２位だからな｡
I normally can't trust him,
but he's 2nd, right after me.
成り行きでさぁ｡
ﾔﾂらから逃げてるところに➡
It just happened to turn out this way.
I was running around when
I bumped into him.
鉢合わせしましてね｡
まぁ １位の旦那なら➡
And I figured since the boss is in
1st place, he wouldn't attack me.
襲ってくることは
ねぇだろうってね｡
ま そっちは
まだ信用できねぇがね｡
Though I can't trust her just yet.
(神楽)なんだ ｺﾗｧ！
お前こそ➡
What was that?!
Aren't you cozying up to Gin-chan
because you're after 1st place?!
銀ちゃんに近づいて
１位の座➡
狙ってんじゃねぇのか!?
あぁん!?
神楽ちゃん！
Kagura-chan!
安心しろ｡ 少なくとも ６位なんて
しみったれた椅子にゃ➡
Don't worry.
At the very least, I'm not interested
in the dirty seat of 6th place.
興味はねぇぜ｡
おい 背中に気をつけろよ｡
Hey, you better watch your back.
２位に興味なくても お前の首なら
いつでも狙ってっからな｡
I don't care about being 2nd, but
I'm always after your head.
(土方)やめろ ｶﾞｷども｡
Cut it out, kids.
ったく どいつもこいつも…
人気投票なんて➡
Honestly, what a sorry sight.
Letting a popularity poll manipulate you...
くだらんもんに
踊らされやがって｡
なんで ｵﾚが こんな目に
遭わなきゃいけねぇんだ？
Why do I have to deal with this?
３位なんざ取るんじゃなかったぜ｡
土方さん！
I wish I had never gotten 3rd place.
Hijikata-san!
Then Hijikata-san can go outside.
じゃあ 土方さんは
外でいいですね｡
下がっていいんだもんね｡
ﾊﾟﾝﾂも順位も➡
You're fine with your rank
going down, right?
You're fine with your underwear and
rank being dragged down, right?
ずり下げられていいんだもんね｡
Open up, damn it!
(土方)開けろ！ ﾃﾒｴら おい！
開けてほしいなら➡
If you want us to open the door, say
that you're happy to be in 3rd.
３位取って嬉しいですって言え｡
ｵﾚたちに負けた 敗残兵が！
Open up!
Even if you're a loser who lost to us.
Who are you calling a loser?!
それでも嬉しいって言え ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｳ！
言ってみろ 土方｡
But say that you're still happy.
Cut it out!
Say it, Hijikata.
お前なら言えるはずだ 土方｡
(土方)殺すぞ ドＳｺﾝﾋﾞ！
You should be able to say it, Hijikata.
I'm gonna kill you, sadistic freaks!
Just kidding, I'm sorry.
(土方)ｳｿｳｿ… ごめん｡
３位取って 超嬉しい！
I'm super happy about being 3rd!
最高！ 開けろ～っ！
It rules!
Open up!
(近藤)ﾊｯﾊｯﾊ… まったく
しかたがないﾔﾂらだ｡
What a hopeless bunch.
なんやかんやで
順位が気にかかるらしい｡
Despite all that talk, they
care about their ranking.
(長谷川)１位だ２位だって
何が嬉しいんだか➡
What's so great about being 1st or 2nd?
This old man can't understand.
正直わからん おじさんは｡
Yeah, no kidding.
(近藤)あ～ ﾎﾝﾄにね｡
ﾎﾞｸらくらい大人になると➡
Once you're our age, that
stuff no longer matters.
正直 どうでもいいですよね
そういうの｡
全然 低くても平気だし｡
I'd be completely fine with a low ranking.
１位も２位も
たいして変わらんですよ｡
And there wouldn't be much difference
if I was 1st or 2nd.
(長谷川)うん｡ どうせ
見てくれだけで選ばれた➡
Yeah, it's just a cheap ranking
based off of looks.
薄っぺらいﾗﾝｷﾝｸﾞだ 正直
勝手にやってくれって感じだよね｡
Quite frankly, they can do
whatever they want.
That's not what we're focused on.
ｵﾚたち そういうとこで
勝負してねぇし～｡
だって 嬉しい？
そんなんで 上位に入って｡
I mean, can you be happy about a high
ranking for such superficial reasons?
ｵﾚは 全然わからねぇや｡
I don't get it.
I could rank higher if I really wanted to.
上位取ろうと思えば
取れますしね｡
あえて取ってないっていうか…｡
But I'm purposely not doing that.
ｼﾞｬﾗｼﾞｬﾗ着飾れば
そりゃ 取れるだろうけど➡
After all, I could dress myself
up to rank higher,
まぁ それは違うだろ！
っていうね…｡
but that wouldn't feel right, yeah?
かっこよさっていうのは
もっと内側から➡
You want to be cool on the inside.
にじみ出るもんじゃないか
っていうね｡
そういう勝負なら
勝手にやってくださいって｡
They can play that game if they want.
こっちは 自然体で
勝負してるわけだから｡ ﾎﾝﾄにね｡
We're going all-natural.
Honestly...
勝手に ﾗﾝｷﾝｸﾞされてるだけで
ちょっと腹立つもん｡
It's a little annoying when
they arbitrarily rank us.
一緒にしてんじゃねぇよ！
みたいな｡
I'm all, don't lump me
with the rest of them!
票入れてんじゃねぇよ！
みたいな｡
I'm all, don't vote for me!
逆に 順位低くて
嬉しい！ みたいな｡
I'm probably happier with a lower rank.
あ～ わかる！ わかる！ ﾎﾝﾄにね｡
Man, I know what you mean.
Seriously, only a few can understand.
わかるﾔﾂだけ
わかってくれればいいのよ！
I mean, just look.
だって これ！
I don't understand how he's 4th.
４位とか
意味わかんないですよね！
何もやってませんよ？ ｺｲﾂ！
This guy hasn't done anything!
He's in 4th by wrapping a
bandage around his head!
ただ 包帯巻いてるだけで
４位ですよ｡
どうせ たいした理由ねぇくせに
巻いてんでしょ？ これ｡
There probably isn't any
real reason for it.
ﾌｧｯｼｮﾝでしょ？ これ｡
It's a fashion statement.
そうだね… ﾎﾝﾄ そう｡
ｵﾚは 結膜炎だけどね｡
Yeah, you've got that right.
Mine is just a pink eye, by the way.
この７位の
神楽ちゃんの兄ちゃん？
And Kagura's big brother at 7th.
これも わかんないよね｡
急に出てきて ７位って｡
I don't understand this one either.
He came out of nowhere and he's 7th?
だって 悪者でしょう？
Isn't he a bad guy?
ﾁｬｲﾅ服 着てるだけでしょ？
He's just wearing a Chinese outfit.
ﾎﾝﾄに そうです｡
そのとおりです！
You're right!
Absolutely right!
ｵﾚは 今日 真選組が
ﾁｬｲﾅ服ﾃﾞｰなだけですけどね｡
In my case, the Shinsengumi's
having Chinese Outfit Day.
To be honest, it's a pain when these other
characters kinda overlap with mine.
正直 迷惑ですよね｡
軽く ｷｬﾗかぶってるっていうかさ｡
(長谷川)かぶってるっていうか
これ ﾊﾟｸﾘだよね？
Overlap? Aren't they ripoffs?
ｷｬﾗ 完全に
ﾊﾟｸられてるよね ｵﾚたち｡
They're total ripoffs of
our characters, yeah?
先に登場したの ｵﾚたちだし｡
We showed up first!
順位は いいけど １回 これは➡
I don't care about the ranking, but
we need to make this clear!
びしっと言ったほうが
いいんじゃないかな うん｡
そうですね！
視聴者に こっちが➡
That's right!
I don't want the audience to
think that we're the ripoffs!
ﾊﾟｸﾘみたいに
思われるのもｲﾔだし｡
Would you cut it out already?
(桂)いい加減にせんか｡
(桂)どっちがﾊﾟｸったとか
あっちがﾊﾟｸったとか➡
Now is not the time to argue about who
did the ripping off, or who was ripped off,
ｵﾚをﾊﾟｸったりとか➡
今は そんなことを
している場合じゃあるまい｡
...or how I've been cuffed up.
桂さん！
Katsura-san!
It doesn't matter if we're the
Anti-Foreigner Faction or Shinsengumi.
攘夷志士も真選組も関係ない｡
Now is the time to unite and
deal with this situation!
今は 一丸となって
事に対処すべきだというのに➡
なぜ ｷｻﾏらには わからんか！
なぜ この錠を解かんか！
Why can't you understand?!
Why won't you uncuff me?!
ﾊｱ… 臆病者どもめ｡
手負いのﾄﾗが そんなに怖いか｡
Cowards...
Are you so scared of a wounded beast?
ﾌﾝ… 確かに
こんな傷さえ負っていなければ➡
It's true that if I wasn't wounded,
幕府の犬などに
おくれはとらなかったわ｡
I wouldn't have been caught
by dogs of the Bakufu.
桂さん…
じゃあ その傷は ﾔﾂらに…｡
Katsura-san, then those
injuries are from...?!
もはや 誰が敵で誰が味方なのか
皆目 見当がつかん｡
I can no longer judge who
is friend and who is foe.
この世には もう
安息の地など➡
No place is safe in this world...
どこにもありはしないぞ｡
桂さん…
回想が おかしいんですけど…｡
Katsura-san, there's something
wrong with that flashback.
安息の地っていうか
これ ｻﾌｧﾘﾊﾟｰｸですよね？
No place is safe?
Isn't that a safari park?
ｻﾌｧﾘ 自転車で行って
やられましたよね？ これ｡
You got injured riding a
bicycle through there?
The nightmare began when I decided that
I wanted to see those paws close-up.
肉球を 間近で見たいと思ったのが
すべての悪夢の始まりか… ｸｯ…｡
Curses...
ｸｯ… じゃねえだろ｡ ﾊﾞｶだろ ｵﾒｴ｡
Curses, my ass!
You're an idiot!
前にも こんなこと
やってたよな？ お前｡
You've done this before, haven't you?!
I don't care what happens!
知らんぞ どんなことになっても｡
You can all...
みんな… みんな 肉球に包まれて
死んでしまえばいいんだ!!
You can all die covered by paws!
ｱﾝﾀだけ死んでください｡
ｱﾝﾀだけ 別件で死んでください｡
You can die by yourself.
You can die by yourself
from a separate case.
ところで ｱﾝﾀ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさんは？
Anyway, where's Elizabeth-san?
まさか ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさんだけ置いて
逃げてきたんじゃないでしょうね｡
Don't tell me you ditched
Elizabeth-san and ran.
(物音)
うっ… あの… すみません…｡
Uh, sorry...
なんか 見ちゃいけないもの
見ちゃったんですけど…｡
I think I just saw something
I wasn't supposed to.
ﾏｽｺｯﾄたちの ﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛした覇権争い
目撃しちゃったんですけど｡
I just saw mascots in a bloody
battle for supremacy.
以上 20位より上位の
８人と２匹だ｡
So here we have eight people
plus two pets from the top 20.
まあ このあたりまでなら
裏切ることもねえだろ｡
Well, I'm guessing that nobody in the
room is going to do any backstabbing.
いや… ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ 不安なんですけど｡
You'll pay for that once we get back.
Um... I'm pretty worried about that.
全員 腹に一物抱えてそうな人
ばっかなんですけど｡
They're all people who don't know
how to hold back their anger.
That's it, Sadaharu!
とりあえずだ 事が収まるまで
このﾎﾃﾙでろう城する｡
Anyway, we'll be hiding out in this
hotel until everything's over.
ここの旦那とは 古い知り合いでな
話は つけてある｡
The manager here's an
old friend of mine.
I've explained everything.
そのへんの心配は いらねえ｡
We won't need to worry.
ほとぼりが冷めるまで
動かねえほうが いいだろう｡
We'll want to stay put until the
excitement's died down.
Excitement?
ほとぼり？ ｿｲﾂは
いつ冷めるもんなんだ？
When are they going to calm down?
そもそも
冷める保証はあるのか？
Hell, are you even sure that
they're going to calm down?
その いつ来るか わからんときを
この胸ｸｿ悪い連中と➡
I have to wait around with a bunch
of pests for god knows how long?
顔つき合わせて
ず～っと待ってろっていうのか？
土方さん 人気投票
っていうものはね➡
Hijikata-san, a popularity poll
たくさんの読者に
協力してもらって➡
can only work when lots
of readers participate.
成立してるんです｡
Don't you find it wrong when people
try to twist that for personal gain?
これを 個人の私利私欲で
ねじ曲げようなんて➡
そんなの
おかしいと思いませんか？
ﾎﾞｸらは 自分の順位を➡
We have a duty to protect our own rank.
どんなことをしても
守る義務がある｡
みんなが与えてくれた
この数字を➡
Aren't we obligated to protect the
number that's been given to us?
守る義務が
あるんじゃないですか？
まあ さすがに
準主役でありながら➡
Well, a secondary main character doesn't
want to be any lower than 8th.
８位以下は ないもんな｡
面目 丸つぶれだもんな｡
That'd be pathetic.
これ以上
下がりたくないよな｡
You don't want to drop any lower, yeah?
つうか ８位の時点で
もう軽くないよね？ ひどいよね？
In fact, 8th is already pretty bad.
Really bad. A real shame.
すごく残念だった｡ 銀さん
なんか悪いことしたなって思った｡
I was wondering if I'd done
something wrong.
そういう意味じゃねえし!!
That's not what I mean!
ﾎﾞｸだって 最初は不服だった｡
I was unhappy in the beginning.
人気投票なんて
なければいいのにって…｡
I thought that popularity
polls shouldn't exist.
でも 山崎さんと
約束したんです｡
But I promised Yamazaki-san!
((山崎:地味… ｷｬﾗ…
１位の座だけは➡
Th-The number one position
for a boring character...
ま… 守り… 通す…))
You must... protect it at all... cost...
新八の八は ８位の八です｡
The "pachi" in Shinpachi
[pachi/hachi = kanji for eight]
is the eight for 8th place.
We all must hold on...
みんなで
守り通そうじゃないですか｡
To our own numbers...
己の数字を… 己の役割を｡
Our own roles...
力を合わせれば きっとできる｡
I'm sure we can do this
if we work together!
ﾎﾞｸたちなら…｡
If we're together...!
当たりめぇだろ｡
Of course we can.
If you can't guard a castle with
this lot, it's a lost cause.
このﾒﾝﾂで守りきれねえ城なら
誰が残ったって落城すらぁ｡
But the strongest castle will fall without
a fight if it's collapsing from the inside.
だが どんな堅強な城も➡
内側が ほころび始めれば
戦わずして たやすく落ちる｡
裏切るんじゃねえぞ｡
Don't turn on us.
Hah. Same to you.
ｹｯ そっちこそな｡
That's great, Gin-san.
やりましたね 銀さん｡
これなら なんだかいけそうです｡
We have a chance now.
ああ でかしたぜ 新八｡
Yeah, well done, Shinpachi.
いい芝居だった｡
えっ!?
That was a nice little act.
Huh?
土方さん
たまにはやりますね｡
Hijikata-san, you show occasional
flashes of brilliance.
ｱｲﾂら完全に信じ込んでましたぜ｡
They were completely fooled.
えっ 信じ込む？
どういうこと それ？ えっ？
Fooled?
What do you mean?
Huh?
(２人)どういうことって
決まってんだろ｡
Shouldn't that be obvious?
ｱｲﾂら蹴落として ｵﾚたちが
首位 独占すんだよ！
We're going to kick them down
so we can dominate the top!
[Popularity Poll Arc]
はぁ～ なんてこった｡
I don't believe this...
銀さんたち上位陣なら➡
I went to Gin-san and the other higher ranked members
believing they wouldn't plan anything bad,
よからぬことは考えないと踏んで
助けを求めにきたけど➡
結局 ここも外と変わらない｡
but it wasn't any different
from the outside.
結局 １位取ったって
今度は また別の欲が出てくる｡
Even if you place 1st, you end up
being driven by a different greed.
Humans are such greedy creatures...
いったい どこまで
欲深い生き物なんだ➡
人間ってﾔﾂは｡
ここまで戦場になったら➡
If this place turns into a battlefield, the
popularity poll will be a complete mess.
本当に人気投票は ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬだ｡
なんとかしないと｡
I have to do something.
In any case, I need to
be wary of the outside.
とりあえず 外への警戒だけは
怠れない！
すぐには 銀さんたちも
動きを見せないだろう｡
Gin-san and the others won't
make a move immediately.
We'll have a real mess on our
hands if this place is attacked.
ここに襲撃を受けたら
それこそﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬだ！
I need to gauge the outside situation.
外の状況は 把握しておかないと！
ん？ あれは… ９位の月詠さん！
That's...
Tsukuyo-san in 9th place.
なんで こんなところ
ほっつき歩いてるんだ？
Why is she walking around here?
あの順位で外にいたら
下位のいいｴｻだ！
If she strolls around outside with that ranking,
she'll be targeted by the lower ranked!
異変に
気づいてないのか!?
Hasn't she noticed the trouble going on?
Should I call Tsukuyo-san over here?
月詠さんも こっちへ呼ぶか…｡
いや ここも安全とは言い難いし｡
No, I'm not sure that it'd be safer here.
あっ！
That's...!
あれは 姉上！
Sis!
((お妙:じゃあ 182話以降は…｡
Then starting from episode 182...
(さっちゃん)
もう出なくていいわよね))
She shouldn't need any
more screen time...
That's right!
そうだ！ あの人たち
月詠さんを狙ってるんだった！
They're after Tsukuyo-san!
月詠さんが危ない！
でも 今 彼女を ここへ呼べば➡
Tsukuyo-san's in danger!
But if I call to her now,
あの猛獣どもも ここへ!?
it'll also draw in those wild beasts!
《いったい どうすれば…
このまま見殺しにするのか？
What do I do...?
Do I leave her out to dry?
どうしよう… どうすれば…》
What do I do?
What should I do...?!
Tsukuyo-san! Look out!
月詠さん 危ない！
(月詠)ん？
Ah, sorry about that.
ああ すまない｡
ﾀﾞﾒだ！ 遅かった！
聞こえなかったか!?
It's no use! It's too late!
She didn't hear me!
Hold it right there!
ちょっと待たんか～い！
Hey, big girl...
おい ねえちゃん ｱ… ｱﾝﾀ➡
Wh-What do you think you're doing?
なに さらしてけつかんねん これ｡
ｱﾈｺﾞの15位が これ
取れてしもうてるやんけ～！
The Boss Lady's 15th has fallen off!
《あっ… 当たり屋だ～!!》
Ah! It's a hit-and-run scam!
お前 これ どないしてくれんじゃ
ﾎﾞｹ こら ｶｽ！
How are you gonna make up
for this, you stupid idiot?!
完全にﾔｸｻﾞの手口だよ｡
ｱｲﾂらﾔｸｻﾞ以外の何者でもないよ！
That's such a yakuza trick!
They're being nothing but a yakuza!
ｱﾈｺﾞの15位が これ➡
Look, the Boss Lady's 15th
has been scratched!
ちょっと
傷入ってもうてるやんけ！
ｵﾒｴ 弁償じゃ
済まされへんで こりゃ！
You won't be able to pay
your way out of this one!
どないするつもりじゃ～!!
What ya gonna do?!
How did it get scratched?!
傷って何だよ!?
つうか あれ 着脱可能だったの!?
I mean, those things are detachable?!
すまぬ｡ よそ見をしていたもので｡
ちゃんと洗って返す｡
Forgive me.
I wasn't paying attention.
I'll wash it and return it.
ごめんなさい 月詠さん！
ﾎﾞｸのせいです!!
I'm sorry, Tsukuyo-san!
It was my fault!
You won't be able to wash away the dirt
that's been thrown onto our emblem.
(九兵衛)組の代紋に
泥を塗っておいて➡
洗ったではすまへんで｡
ちょっと事務所まで
ご足労 願おうか｡
Could you come down
to the office with us?
代紋？ あれ代紋なの!?
Emblem?! That's a emblem?!
(お妙)猿飛 九兵衛
そのへんにしとき｡
Sarutobi, Kyubei.
That's enough.
That young lady didn't do it on purpose.
こちらのお嬢さんも
悪気があったわけやないんや｡
そないに ｶﾀｷﾞいじめたるなや｡
みっともない｡
It's despicable to bully
an honest girl like that.
しかし ｱﾈｺﾞ！
But, Boss Lady!
Forgive the disturbance
my young girls caused.
えらい すんまへんでしたな｡
ｳﾁの若いﾓﾝが｡
申し訳ないことをした｡
I've done you wrong.
It seems that you've lost
something important...
何か大切なものを失ったようで…｡
It doesn't matter.
ええねや もう｡
気にせんといて｡
Don't worry about it.
どの道 わしゃもう
この世界から➡
I was going to clean up from
this business anyway.
足洗うつもりやったんや｡
ｱﾈｺﾞ！
Boss Lady?!
15位なんて
半端な看板背負ってても➡
A half-assed 15th sign won't
get me anywhere.
もうどないにもならへん｡
Our methods are too old.
わしらのやり方は もう古い｡
I already realized that.
そないなこと
もうとっくに気づいとったんや｡
でも いつかｸﾞｯｽﾞ出るんちゃうか｡
But I kept thinking they might
sell character goods,
いつか ｷｬﾗｿﾝ出るんちゃうか｡
or release character songs,
いつか ﾌﾟﾘﾝｾｽﾌﾟﾘﾝｾｽみたいに➡
or let us form a unit like
PRINCESS PRINCESS,
[Note: PRINCESS PRINCESS, or Puri-Puri,
was a Japanese girl band from the 80's.]
ﾕﾆｯﾄ組ませてもらえるん
ちゃうかって ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙ ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙ｡
and kept hoping and hoping...
気づいたら ｱﾆﾒ４年目も
もう３ｸｰﾙ目に突入しとった｡
The next thing I know, we're already
half way done with the fourth season.
けど 押し寄せる時代の波には
さすがのﾌﾟﾘﾌﾟﾘも勝たれへん｡
But even Puri-Puri was unable
to beat the new wave.
ﾌﾟﾘﾌﾟﾘの時代は終わった｡
Puri-Puri's time is over...
これからの時代は 新しい波｡
そう ｱﾝﾀらﾊﾟﾌｭｰﾑの時代なんや｡
This is a new age...
Yes...
The age of you, the Perfume.
[Note: Perfume is a Japanese
female technopop group.]
ｱﾝﾀのおかげで未練も切れたわ｡
Thanks to you, I no longer
have any regrets.
ようやく解散できる｡
ありがとうな 引導渡してくれて｡
I finally disband the group.
Thank you for the guidance.
あとのことは 頼むで
わしらのぶんまで ｴﾚｸﾄるんやで｡
I leave the rest to you.
Electro-on for our sake.
Ah, wait up.
(月詠)ああ ちょっと待ちなんし｡
I found this lying around.
これ 落ちてたんだけど
ひょっとして これも➡
Does it belong to you?
ぬしらのものではないのか？
《ちぎった！
月詠さん 自分の順位ちぎった！》
She snapped it off!
Tsukuyo-san snapped
her own ranking off!
いや それｷﾐのじゃ｡
いや 落ちてた そこに｡
Uh, isn't that yours...?
No, it was just lying there.
ちょっと 月詠さん！
Hey, Tsukuyo-san!
Just lying there? You're bleeding.
(さっちゃん)
落ちてたって 血出てるやん｡
Your tore it off, so there's
blood everywhere.
無理やり
ちぎったから血まみれやん｡
I just fell over there.
ちょっと
そこで転んだ｡ 気にせんといて｡
Don't worry about it.
It's okay, Tsukuyo-san!
いいよ 月詠さん！ そんな
ﾔﾂらに気使わなくていいって！
You don't need to be considerate
to that lot!
お嬢さん
気持はありがたいんやけど➡
Young lady, I appreciate the thought,
but I can't accept that.
さすがに それはもらわれへん｡
Puri-Puri still has its pride.
ﾌﾟﾘﾌﾟﾘにも意地っちゅうもんがある｡
ﾀﾞｲﾔﾓﾝﾄﾞのように かたいﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞが｡
Pride as hard as a diamond.
それに わしだけ
９位になっても意味あらへん｡
Besides, it wouldn't matter
if I became 9th by myself.
そんなんじゃうちのもん みんな
ﾒｼ食わせていかれへんさかい｡
That won't be enough to feed our bunch.
ｱﾈｺﾞ なんか
手はあらへんですかね？
Boss Lady... Isn't there a way?
わしら全員 ９位に
なれるような方法が｡
A way for all of us to become 9th?
Don't be foolish.
無理言いな｡ もうええのや｡
It's okay.
ほなな｡ わしらのぶんまで
ﾀﾞｲﾔﾓﾝﾄﾞｴﾚｸﾄるんやで｡
Electro-on the diamonds for our sake.
(月詠)ああ
ちょっと待ちなんし｡
Oh, wait up.
これ落としたら
なんか４つに割れたぞ｡
This broke into four pieces
after I dropped it.
《ちぎった！ 今度は順位を
更に４つにちぎった！》
She shattered it!
Now she shattered her ranking
into four pieces!
これ みんなでわければ
ひょっとして➡
Perhaps we can all be 9th
if we divide this among us?
全員９位に
なれるんじゃないかな？
I really doubt that.
まさか
そんなこと さすがにそれは｡
It'd be a stretch...
待て！ ちょっと待て！
それはないだろ それはﾀﾞﾒだろ！
Wait! Hold it right there!
That won't do! That can't work!
ほな こんなんどうですか？ ｱﾈｺﾞ｡
Then how about this, Boss Lady?
わしら ４人合わせて
ﾀﾞｲﾔﾓﾝﾄﾞﾊﾟﾌｭｰﾑで➡
The four of us can join together as
Diamond Perfume at 9th place.
まとめて９位ってことで｡
誰が ﾊﾟﾌｭｰﾑだ そんなのありなの！
Who are you calling Perfume?!
That's allowed?!
そんなやり方もあったの！
You can do that?!
That's great. I love that.
ええわ
それええ 名案やで九兵衛！
A brilliant idea, Kyubei.
ほな ｱﾈｺﾞ わしらも
ｴﾚｸﾄﾛってええんですか！
Hey, Boss Lady. We can electro-on too?
わしらも下手な
ﾛﾎﾞｯﾄﾀﾞﾝｽしてええんですか！
We can also do the really
bad robot-dance?!
な なんてこった｡
まさか一滴も血を流さず➡
I-I don't believe this...
I didn't expect them to conquer their target
without a single drop of blood shed...
無血開城してしまうなんて｡
蹴落とすのではない
吸収することで➡
They climbed up to 9th by absorbing
instead of destroying...
９位までのしあがってくるなんて｡
《ﾔﾂら ﾊﾟﾌｭｰﾑなんて
かわいいもんじゃない》
They're nowhere as cute as Perfume...
あれは…｡
They're...
あれは！
They're...!
Vacuum!
A terrible vampire unit which absorbs everything
to become their own flesh, Vacuum!
何でも吸収し
己の血肉にしてしまう➡
戦慄の吸血ﾕﾆｯﾄ ﾊﾞｷｭｰﾑだ！
That's right.
そうや わしらだけじゃなんやし➡
It wouldn't be right with
only the four of us.
神楽ちゃんも
入れてやろうやないかい｡
We should also invite Kagura-chan.
６位！ 今度は
６位を吸収するつもりだ！
6th!
Now they intend to absorb 6th place!
《ﾀﾞﾒだ！ これ以上
ｱｲﾂらを好き勝手にさせては｡
This won't do!
I can't let them have their way!
早くみんなに伝えに
行かないと！》
I have to tell everyone!
うわ～っ！
《見られた！
ﾊﾞｷｭｰﾑに勘づかれた！》
They saw me!
I've been noticed by Vacuum!
This is bad!
《ﾏｽﾞｲ！ ﾔﾂらがのり込んでくる！
They're barging in!
ここももうじき戦場だ！ 襲撃に
備えて守りをかためないと》
This place will be a battlefield soon!
We need to tighten our defenses
in preparation!
銀さん！ 襲撃です！ 仲間同士で
争ってる場合じゃないですよ！
Gin-san!
We're under attack!
This isn't the time to be fighting
among ourselves!
仲間同士で争う？
そうかい ﾃﾒｴらやっぱり｡
Fighting among ourselves?
I see...
So you all...
ﾊﾅからｵﾚたち
裏切るつもりだったんだな｡
were planning on turning on
us from the beginning.
お 沖田さん
ち 違うんです 沖田さん｡
O-Okita-san...!
Y-You've got it wrong, Okita-san.
今のは そういう意味じゃなくて｡
That wasn't what I meant...
ﾌﾝ とぼけちゃいけねえよ｡
あれを見ろ｡
Don't play dumb.
Look over there.
Ha-Hasegawa-san?!
はっ 長谷川さん！
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
First Yamazaki-san, and
now Hasegawa-san...
And the Diamond Perfume
is already on our doorstep!
What is going to happen
to this popularity poll?!
[Popularity Poll can...]
If this is the result, then
popularity polls can...
[The intense survival battle surrounding the rankings leads to a showdown between Diamond Perfume and the higher ranking men!]
[Who will be in 1st place when
the ranking battle ends?!]
[See you next time.]